Kavindra Nikhurpa

Software Developer

Address Haldwani, Uttarakhand, 263139

Phone +918826093188

E-mail kavi.nikhurpa@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/knikhurpa

Website https://www.nikhurpa.co.in

Proficient software developer adept in a variety of programming languages and technologies such as Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and SQL. Driven and proactive with proven history of going above and beyond to contribute to team objectives. Looking to utilize 3+ years of management experience and problem-solving skills to create highquality software.

Work History

2018-06 -**Deputy Branch Manager** Current

Union Bank of India

- Oversaw a variety of banking services and assisted the manager in meeting profit, performance and customer service targets.
- Managed the financial activities of the branch and worked to gain and retain customers by maintaining high standards of customer service.
- Built strong client relationships which translated into increased credit portfolio.
- Developed several campaigns to increase profit through branch operations and cross-selling.
- Identified and capitalized on community business opportunities with effective networking.
- Uncovered and resolved strategic and tactical issues impacting business operations.

2016-09 -**Full Stack Developer Intern** 2017-04

All Domain Soft. Pvt. Ltd.

- Created modules in various web projects using a variety of tools including JavaScript, ColdFusion, HTML/CSS, and Bootstrap.
- Designed, coded, and debugged web applications and software based on client's specifications.
- Learned new emerging technologies and took initiative to offer creative solutions.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS for integration and crossbrowser compatibility.

Skills

- Python
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Flutter
- Dart

- Linux
- Database Management
- ColdFusion
- Networking
- Relationship building and management

Education

2012-08 - 2016-08

Bachelor of Technology: Electronics & Communication Engineering

Dehradun Institute of Technology - Dehradun, Uttarakhand

Projects

Discord Bot:

- A Python discord bot built with a variety of tools including the Discord API, quotes API and a cloud computing platform called Repl.it.
- https://github.com/knikhurpa/discord-bot

Infinite days of code:

- An ever-growing collection of Python scripts.
- https://github.com/knikhurpa/infinite-days-of-code

Business Card App:

- A business card android application made using Flutter and Dart.
- https://github.com/knikhurpa/business-card-flutter

Languages

- **English** Full Professional Proficiency
- Hindi Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- Japanese Elementary Proficiency

Interests

- Learning languages
- Playing guitar
- Blogging
- Mountain biking